Ooh, that's not good. Timing of this
Federal Reserve dropping a bomb that
they might end up hiking rates next
month because Kevin Walsh made mistakes.
We'll talk about what just came out in a
moment is very eerie.
See, the dot bubble burst when the
Federal Reserve went back to rate hikes
after 2 years and 3 months. And they
ended up hiking rates six times. They
hiked rates in June of 99, August,
November. Then in 2000, they hiked in
February. So basically like, you know,
they skipped a meeting and hiked again.
March of 2000, and then in May of 2000,
we got the final nail in the coffin, a
50 basis point hike. rates ended up
going up 1.75%
from 4.75 to 6.5% to tame inflation.
That's six rate hikes. But now you're
getting calls for us starting with three
rate hikes and starting as soon as next
month. Now, why is that eerie? Well,
what's eerie about this is the market
topped right in the midst of this rate
hike cycle. The market ended up topping
in March of 2000, which was about 9
months after their first hike. And the
timing is strange. See, the Fed's nail
in the coffin.com
hike came exactly
38 months since the last time they had a
Fed rate hike.
If the Fed hikes September 16th, they
will be hiking exactly
38 months since the last time we've had
an interest rate hike.
That is weird timing.
Obviously, it's not a perfect overlap,
right? The last time 30 it was 38 months
from their last hike to well their last
hike again. This time it would be 38
months from the Fed's last hike to the
Fed's first hike. But who knows? It
could be their first and last. We don't
know. The point is 38 month like gap
there. Little weird kind of coincidental
we'll call it. Maybe we'll call it that
because anytime we make a comparison
between now and the dot bubble, people
start freaking out and lashing out in
the comments as if I haven't already
done the research myself. But people
lash out and start going, "Kevin, this
time is different. Earnings are so much
better and more robust this time. You
can't compare to the past, you know.
Everyone has rabbit hole on their phone
today. They can all buy the dip. This
time is different, bro.
These people are going to have a
seizure. Feel bad sometimes when I see
the freak. It's like, imagine you'd be
so angry
about the news that you're going to
freak out in the comments at a YouTuber.
My reaction to that is
what the
[laughter]
Anyway, all right, let's uh let's focus
here and be a little bit more
professional.
I think that's like the opposite of what
we do on this channel. But anyway, uh
Kevin Walsh is starting to acknowledge
that he's uh really effed up with his
left of the decimal speech and this is
uh creating some increased potential for
us to get a rate hike because now he's
essentially got to do damage control for
that speech. The left of the decimal
speech was his first speech where he's
like, "Look, we're not going to do
forward guidance, but we're going to
forward guide that we're only going to
focus on inflation to the left of the
decimal." And then the bond market is
like, "That's dumb. That's tarded. Um,
we'll hike a lot for you." And we ended
up seeing the 2-year and the 10-year,
you could look at the charts yourself,
skyrocket in the intermedating period
between his first meeting and his second
meeting.
Kevin Worsh then at his next meeting is
like, "Wow, I take comfort in how well
the market has responded to me being an
idiot."
Obviously, he didn't say the latter
part, but he did literally use the word,
"I take comfort in the fact that rates
have gone up this much." Well, the
market doesn't really like that because
in my opinion, the bond market is
basically pricing in the increased risk
premium the bond market needs to justify
for Kevin Walsh losing credibility,
providing less guidance and therefore
increasing the risk of bond market
volatility. When the risk of volatility
increases or the perceived future
volatility of an asset goes up, your
discount should also go up. Let me
explain that in simple English.
Hey yo, if there's a chance this stock's
going to go down a whole lot more, a
whole lot faster, I'mma pay less for it.
[laughter]
That's basically what's happening in the
bond market. Uh, and that makes sense.
So now you've got other committee
members basically trying to send
forecasts for him. They're almost
seeding his power. You know, while Wars
is trying to be dark, Qashqari is going
on his circuit saying we should be
raising rates. We know Hammock and Logan
are talking about raising rates. You've
got Qashqari literally saying, "I don't
trust the Iranians." Hormuz is
uncertain. Energy costs are high. The
consumer and labor is hanging in.
Corporate earnings are doing great.
Doesn't sound like rates are restrictive
to me. Mary Daily is also warning that
higher inflation could trigger rate
hikes soon. You got a whole chorus of
Fed folks.
A whole kumbaya going, "Hey,
might have to start raising rates." Bank
of America is not helping. They're
jumping in going, "Hey,
we actually think we should see three
raid hikes uh this year. We should wait,
hold on. We need the right mug for
this." Oh, we should see three raid
hikes. Once in September, then in
October, and then in December. And you
know what you could do to set it all up?
Jackson Hole. Oh, great. We're back to
Jackson Hole. Yeah, Jackson Hole is this
month. Oh, I'll be live streaming it.
But Jackson Hole is literally at the end
of this month, August 27th to August
29th, and he's usually the keynote
speaker, the keynote fool. [laughter]
But that's often where they could set up
and sort of fix their mistakes and set
up what's coming. You know, Jerome
Powell set up the, you know, some
ruggins in Jackson Hole before. So, you
know, it's it's a big one to pay
attention to and the entire world tends
to pay attention to it. So, what's
happening now? Well, what's happening
now is this Financial Times piece came
out that su suggests Kevin Worsh to
stick with leanfed messaging. Okay,
that's the headline, which doesn't
really tell us anything. But what's
actually very telling here is people
close to Walsh say he acknowledged he's
made mistakes in his first 10 weeks at
the helm. This is fine. We're not
expecting the knucklehead to be perfect
when he first gets his job, but he also
has a history of being a knucklehead.
you know, he was the guy calling for
rate hikes while the economy was
collapsing in 2008. In 2007, it's like,
we should raise rates. In 2008, we
should raise rates. In 2009, as the
economy is like trying to get footing,
hey, we should raise rates. It was
exactly the wrong call. And he has a
legacy of making exactly the wrong
decision. So, not only does he have to
overcome his legacy of being wrong, now
he has to overcome this, we're only
going to focus on the left of the
decibel. And he's kind of got that like
smug kind of glide glib, however you say
it, attitude anyway, where it's just I'm
going to act professional, but I'm
actually I just got a stick up my butt.
Yeah, there's a puppet down there
guiding me. It's actually Donald Trump.
[laughter]
Um, which apparently Donald Trump has
been ringing this guy off the hook.
Apparently Donald Trump will go as often
as calling Kevin Wars like three or four
times a week and then he'll go like long
stretches without calling him and he'll
call him again for like three or four
times and and he does this over and over
again and he's asking for advice about
like what about AI? What about Iran? Now
hopefully I mean we could presume that
Kevin Worsh is telling him the right
thing which is like you better make a
deal otherwise I'm gonna have to hike
you know uh whatever but what we have to
think about is in this article right
here we have talk about hey well
inflation expectations are still stable
fine I mean you could zoom out on any
chart and call it stable uh you could
zoom out on uh memory stocks if you zoom
out far enough and call them stable
>> [laughter]
>> technically call anything stable. But uh
right here, look at this line. This is
the one that really matters today. Kevin
Walsh would be prepared to raise
interest rates at September's meeting if
inflation readings released in coming
weeks are hot. Ah, great. Okay. So, that
really sets us up to be pretty live for
and and we should be pretty prepared for
a rate hike uh over the next well,
frankly, meeting. And every data point
that leads into that meeting is going to
be really important. This was something
that we talked about in the alpha report
yesterday morning. And I'm just sharing
this with you. It's not a pitch.
Yesterday morning, I said, "Look, we
just had two epic days of releveraging.
Monday and Tuesday, massive days of
releveraging. Be cautious here because
we have jobs data coming up on Friday."
this Fed uh Financial Times piece that
came out today actually makes that jobs
data tomorrow even more important. But
think about that. Yesterday morning, the
market's up, you know, whatever we were
up yesterday. I think we were at 7:25.
Yeah, we were at the 725 line yesterday
morning. So, here we are in the alpha
report yesterday morning and I'm like,
hey, we just had two phenomenal days. Be
cautious. the market tends to sell down
before we get especially after a big
rally, you know, a big releveraging,
people are going to take profits, but
you tend to sell down before a big
catalyst event like a jobs report. And
so yesterday was a day of caution. And
so look at what happened. Look at what
ended up happening. So we made that call
right here in the alpha report
documented and the market literally
bled. We we fell from 725 all the way
down to 7:15. You know, today we're
teetering. Okay, you know, hey, can we
can we hold on to 715? Can we hold on to
this level? Some of this is by the
dipping on SanDisk and Western Digital,
which are, you know, still still red
even though they're getting dip bot,
which is nice. But I mean, focus for a
moment. This makes tomorrow very
important. That call in the alpha report
was great, but I want to be clear. This
makes tomorrow very important.
Now, I'll probably be live earlier
tomorrow in the course member liveream
so we could really analyze this jobs
data. Uh, and I encourage you to join
me. You could always join over at
meetke.com. Uh, August 14th is when the
coupon expires. So, you got some time,
but you may as well join so you could be
part of it. Tomorrow, we'll cover the
jobs report. Uh, you could join using
coupon code vacation green. Remember,
you could write this off on your taxes.
Most people do verify that with your
CPA. Yet, every single course is bundled
into the alpha membership. you get all
the trade alerts, uh, you know, our
private live streams, the fundamental
analysis, the stocks we're buying, the
stocks we're selling, whatever, the
trade alerts, right? You get those as
well. So, go check that out. Uh, but
let's think for a moment what the
catalyst calendar actually looks like
and then let's also think about the
Greenspan mistake. So, well, let's
actually start with the Greenspan
mistake. Uh, by May of 2000, uh, Allan
Greenspan had finished his rate hike
cycle of six rate hikes. And that rate
hike cycle was widely considered to have
burst the dot bubble. And it's possible
it's because funding costs went up
1.75%. I mean, it's quite a bit. But
you're already seeing funding costs go
up. I mean, Google's coming out raising
another $25 billion. So, we're getting
the resucketing. It's sort of like the
return of the suck. You know, we're
going to start having like Star Wars
related names here. You know, the rise
of the suck, the return of the suck or
the whatever, right? [laughter]
The suck strikes back.
The suck 2.0. I don't whatever you want
to call it. The suck episode 4.
[laughter]
Uh anyway, so
we saw Coreweave had to raise interest
rates on their offering to over 10% to
raise money for their uh data centers.
SpaceX had to raise interest rates to
attract capital to actually, you know,
fill their bond offering. Google's going
out raising another $25 billion in sort
of a laddered bond offering. That's in
addition to the $40 billion of shares
that they want to dump onto the market,
which as of June 30th, they haven't done
yet. Who knows? Maybe they did it in
July, but we don't we don't know that
yet.
Uh on top of that, when Allan Greenspan
finished his sort of six rate hikes
there and funding costs went up by
1.75%. It's worth noting that treasuries
were sitting at like a 5-year high at
that time. Well, if you now look at our
Treasury yields, a lot of our treasuries
are sitting at long-term highs as well.
I think our uh 30-year just hit a Let's
go look at the 30-year Treasury really
quick, cuz we hit a high right after the
July meeting that was pretty nasty. I
want to say it was almost 5
uh let's see 30-year Treasury. I don't
know why it's so hard to load. There it
is. Uh yeah, 5 like17 5.19 is where we
sit right now. Uh oh, there we go. Okay,
here it is. So after the July meeting,
we actually had 5.27
there for a moment at the closing price.
That's remarkable. And so if you zoom
out, that's a 5-year high on the 30-year
Treasury. And if you zoom out, this is
actually the highest level we've been on
the these treasuries since either
we're at about 2006 pricing, but our
peak would have brought us back to about
2004. So, this is a massive high. We're
talking about a 20 to 22year high on the
30-year Treasury. And uh that moment
when the Fed was raising rates in the
dotcom bubble also marked a multi-year
high in treasuries. And so don't just
think about the Fed's rates. Think about
what that means for funding costs for
the companies that are trying to spend
more on capex that are trying to raise
money. The stocks that got hit the worst
as the market started selling off
through that rate cycle were of course
tech stocks. Cisco, Intel, Oracle all
crashed then. And the NASDAQ 100 ended
up crashing 78% from March 2000 to
October of 2002.
So that's a 2 and a half year crash.
That's like, you know, two remember 2022
when we had like a 10-month stock market
crash. Okay, multiply that by uh three.
You know, that's that's an extended
period of pain and suffering. Uh, and
I'm not saying that's going to happen.
What I'm saying is the risk is the more
funding costs go up, the less
sustainable these capex cycles become.
So, you just every time you get these
rate hikes or even just bond market
yields go up, the riskier the market
gets. And that's the that's the point of
rate hikes anyway, right? Or I mean
that's that's the point. Rate hikes are
designed to cool inflation and cool
capex. That's the mechanism by which
it's supposed to happen. But you're also
getting bond market investors who are
saying, "Hey, I'm going to need to get
compensated more for the risk." Right?
So, not good. Um, this Financial Times
piece also, in my opinion, suggests that
there's a little bit of a desire to
maybe flip. Okay, maybe we do need some
forward guidance.
Duh. [laughter]
Yeah. What? You don't want the market to
be rugpulled, huh? Isn't that what we
learned with Japan and the Japanese
carry trade? That, you know, forward
guidance is actually useful. Of course,
then then you get the people on usually
on X that are like forward guidance is
Keynesian. That's nasty, disgusting
leftist crap.
But as with everything, you know, people
with a higher IQ than the typical uh,
you know, SH9T poster on on X looking
for engagement bait. Uh, that wouldn't
know nuance if it hit him in the butt.
um
recognize so so people tend to recognize
that if you didn't have any regulation
in markets
uh and you had a completely free market
which I'm actually a fan of free markets
but I recognize if you had a completely
unregulated market
we would probably be either way closer
to socialism and communism in America
than we already are uh or uh we'd
already be there mostly because the
damage that comes from a completely un
unregulated or unguided market uh is so
much deeper, right? Because you don't
have a government trying to soften the
blow in the bottom, right? Like in other
words, this is sort of what Kevin Walsh
was trying to do in 2008 and 2009. And
there are a lot of people who believe
that are like that's okay, let the
bottom fall out. That's fine. Like I get
that argument. I'm not saying it's a low
IQ argument to say let the bottom fall
out. That's right. Let let it all die. I
get that. I get that argument. I'm
saying not recognizing that there's
another side or there's nuance is the
low IQ move. The high IQ move is I know
I I know there are arguments for letting
the bond letting the market totally
crash and dump and let all the the the
waste uh collapse, all the zombie
companies, let them all fail. Fine. It
doesn't matter to me. We're going to be
fine. Sitting on $100 million of of real
estate and real estate developments and
and securities uh with no bank debt like
so so whatever, man. We're we're we'll
play whatever game. If we're going to go
cut rates to zero and bail everything
out or whatever, fine. We'll we'll play
that game. If we're going to go bottom's
going to fall out, let everything
collapse, we'll play that game, too.
We're ready.
Um but you know I I know not everybody's
that fortunate and and that's why I
recognize that when people say oh we
just don't have the the the government
involved at all or the Fed involved at
all. That creates a lot of human
suffering a lot. Uh and that's why there
is I think a U-turn now on this sort of
forward guidance. It's sort of like the
Fed's not going to have any forward
guidance but but hint hint Kevin Walsh
would be prepared to raise interest
rates at the September meeting.
[laughter]
This is setting up forward guidance
again. They are flip-flopping on us in
real time. And it's crazy because, you
know, sometimes people be like, "Oh,
Kevin, you always say the fence
flip-flopping." They are, dude, they're
flopping around like a fish I just took
out of water and threw it onto the boat
deck and it's flopping around so much it
got itself off the hook and now it's
between everybody's feet. And I'm like,
"Ah, this scaly bastard."
[laughter] you know, somebody pick this
thing up. Anyway, uh so, uh you know,
then despite or like during all of this,
you've now got Bessen lashing out
against Nick Tieros, our homie Nick T.
Listen to this of one of the highlights
of the WASH Fed has been watching
stenographers posing as journalists like
Wall Street Journal's Nick Tanamos Ter I
Tim Timmeros. I always screw up how I
pronounce his name. It's my fault. I'm
too lazy to actually read that. It's Tim
and then
[snorts]
uh reduced to reporting Fed backroom
gossip because they're incapable of
performing real economic or monetary
policy analysis without being spoonfed.
This is basically Bessant saying, "Oh,
it's good we don't have forward
guidance." Meanwhile, you know, it
literally sounds like they're bringing
forward guidance back. So, you know,
Besson already looks like a fool here.
But we like Nick T. We actually think he
not only gives us good uh uh you know
like analysis, he also has been known as
Nikki Leaks to help provide us the
forward guidance. [laughter]
We we we think there have been some text
messages between people at the Fed and
Nick T uh leak stuff during blackout
periods to not shock markets. That is
intentional to make sure you know
markets don't crater uh when the Fed
acts. Of course, you know, Scott Besson
uh is getting a lot of blast back
because he ran in 2024 with Trump
during, you know, the campaign and said,
"Hey, we're going to have a 333 economic
agenda, 3% annual growth, 3% budget
deficits of GDP, and we're going to
increase oil production, uh 3 million
barrels a day." Okay. Well, we didn't do
any of those. Okay. Average annual
growth is closer to 2% like 1.9% annual.
Okay? Not like the quarterly volatile
data. uh budget deficits are like twice
3%. They're like 5.8% uh as of
September. And uh oil production is only
up like half a million barrels a day.57
to be exact. And that's since January of
2025. So that's over an 18-month period.
The only thing with a three in front of
it is inflation.
Thanks, Bessant.
So what matters next? Uh well, we got
some catalyst dates to look at. So, what
matters next is we've got the jobs
report tomorrow. We're expecting 80,000
jobs. Uh a soft number here would
actually be good [laughter] because it
would potentially put a damper on a rate
hike. Uh a blowout number would be
really bad because then it's just all
right, buckle up, we're getting our rate
hike. You know, it's coming. CPI comes
out August 12th. That's 2 days after
Lauren's birthday. August 14th, that's 2
days after CPI.
coupon code expiration. I meet
Kevin.com. Prices are going up. Um we
are we are really getting close. Uh
probably this month uh either by August
14th or by the end of this month, we've
got a big shift coming to pricing. Uh
and so I think you're you're going to
want to get in before that. Uh so, you
know, get it get in here in August
because things are going to change. it's
going to be more expensive. So, um BLS,
uh jobs, the next set. So, the August
job numbers come out September 4th. So,
mark your calendar for that. And then
CPI September 11th. So, then you've got
the Fed meeting on September 16th. And
then, of course, you've got uh the
Jackson Hole meeting on August 27th. So,
we actually got a F kind of rich
catalyst calendar here. You know, it's
uh it's going to be juicy. So, we got
some work to do. Uh, I'll be covering
it. I'll be adding context and clarity
to all of this. So, always make sure
you're here. Uh, I I I know, you know,
some people are like, "But Kevin, you
mentioned the coupon code." It's like,
well, we don't have any sponsors on the
channel. You know, the only thing I I
work to promote is House Hack. Uh, House
Hack and Reinvest. That's it. Uh, that's
where the money goes from the alpha
membership. So, if you join, you're just
helping out out House Hack and Reinvest
and and that's it. You know, I feel like
it's the most transparent thing you
could ask for. I'm not I'm not paid by
Russian bots. I'm not paid by, you know,
third party companies. It's it's uh
YouTube ad revenue and then and then
it's it's house hack. That's it, boys
and girls. You know, and I I think
that's fair. Uh you know, we're not
running sponsored posts in between this.
Uh so, uh you know, I don't know. I I
don't see how you could be any more
transparent.
All right, folks. Thanks so much for
being here. We'll see you next one.
Goodbye. Good luck. Why not advertise
these things that you told us here? I
feel like nobody else knows about this.
>> We'll we'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. You have done so
much. People love you. People look up to
you.
>> Kevin Pra there, financial analyst and
YouTuber. Meet Kevin. Always great to
get your take.